

Ismail Suleimanov

Software Engineer

+90 530 570 2428

ismailmslmnv@gmail.com

★ ismailslmnv.github.io

Sakarya, Turkey

SUMMARY

I am an excited and open to learn developer and junior entrepreneur from Sakarya. I have worked in many projects during collage and early work life. Furthermore, I could define myself as agile, chatty, curious, thoughtful, researcher and bookworm.

EXPERIENCE

08/2020 - 11/2021

Development Team Leader - Scrum Master

Softinyo Bilişim ve Güvenlik Teknolojileri

As a Team Leader, my responsibilities were to plan, budget, execute and control the entire development project. Time to time developed some parts of projects myself, but mostly my duty was to meet up with clients, get their needs, translate it into IT, design the structure of project, create transcripts, design DB schemes, create teams and tasks, control development process, test finished parts of the project and be responsible to the client and the management with progress.

Tech Stack:

- Trello
- Jira
- AWS Device Farm (to run automated tests and demo show)
- CI/CD Pipelines
- Bitbucket
- Lucid Chart
- Excel

01/2020 - 08/2020

Server Side Developer

Softinyo Bilişim ve Güvenlik Teknolojileri

Developed Server side API and Web Management applications during this role. Developed various internal API and performed external API bindings. Mostly used PHP and Python on this role.

Tech Stack:

- MySQLi and PDO (PHP)
- · SQL Injection protection algorithms (both on PHP and Python)
- MySQL DB
- · Python Flask, CherryPy, Django, Django Rest
- · ¡Query and Ajax
- Bootstrap 3 & 4
- · Docker and Containers

Experience gained on:

- · Backend of E-commerce applications
- API development
- · API Gateway development
- · Dockerizing and testing
- · Web administration panel development
- Integrating payment systems (like lyzico, PayTR, Google Pay, PayPal)
- Understanding needs of client and develop proper solution

01/2020 - 08/2020

Mobile Developer

Softinyo Bilişim ve Güvenlik Teknolojileri

As a mobile developer, I was responsible to develop the mobile sides of various projects.

Those projects could be categorized as text based games, e-commerce applications, e-learning platforms and so on.

Mostly used Flutter/Dart for development, but in side of Flutter I used Java(Android) and Xamarin.

Tech Stack and experience gained on while performing this role:

- State Management Solutions on Flutter Provider, GetX
- · Audio packages development
- Package development (Native Android Side)
- UI Development
- Backend Development

03/2019 - 08/2019

Project Consultant And Manager

4M Teknoloji

Managing, Planning and Consulting the Curriculum of Robotics projects for High School level students.

02/2019 - 09/2019

Co-founder and Communication Software Developer

Proiect T4H

Development of Mavlink applications for UAV.

Experience gained on:

PyMavlink,

Dronekit,

Gazebo STL

01/2018 - 07/2018

Educator

4M Teknoloji

Educating basics of electronics and algorithms to 5-15 years old kids.

- Basic sensor and electronics
- C/C++ Coding
- Arduino

10/ - 01/2018

Technical Support Specialist

4M Teknoloji

Technical Support on IT devices (PC, Network, 3D Printers)

EDUCATION

2021

Information Systems Engineering

Sakarya University

Bachelor's Degree

• Founding and Managing very first UAV community and team of the university.

CERTIFICATES

01/2018 - Present

Kubernetes in the Google Cloud

SKILLS

Python Advanced Java Intermediate PHP Advanced Xamarin Advanced Flutter Advanced Arduino Advanced Advanced C# Advanced Sensors And Electronics SQL Expert C++ Beginner

LANGUAGES

EnglishFluentTurkishNativeRussianBasicAzerbaijaniNativeGeorgianIntermediatePolishBasic